<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Wright</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Wright</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Currently In Class</title>
      <link>/blog/currently-in-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/currently-in-class/</guid>
      <description>Needleman-Wunsch Algorithm  We use this to score alignments Here is an example from class on how to do this  sequence 1 = “ACGCTTACCG” sequence 2 = “AGCCTACCCC”  Without the help of these functions, you would have to score alignments by hand like this:  seq1=&amp;quot;ACGCTTACCG&amp;quot; seq2=&amp;quot;AGCCTACCCC&amp;quot; def match_fun(a,b): # Helper function to define match/mismatch scores if a==b: score=1 #match score else: score=-1 #mismatch score return score def needleman(seq1,seq2,gap_penalty=-1): # Needleman-Wunsch algorithm in a funct m=len(seq1) #length of horizontal sequence n=len(seq2) #length of vertical sequence score=np.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>About Me Raised in Colleyville, Texas, I am currently a 4th year Biology student at UT Austin. Growing up, I always had a passion for medicine and am now in the process of interviewing and waiting on acceptances from Medical Schools. I hope to one day work as an Emergency Medicine Physician and also use my passion for business to better hospital operations.
 Education The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX  Bachelor of Science and Arts in Biology Business of Healthcare Certificate GPA: 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The dataset I used, TexasCountyData, was created by merging the data from Texas Education and Employment by county (CountyEducationEmployment) and Texas Income by county (CountyIncome), both obtained from the Texas Association of Counties. The Texas Education and Employment dataset contains the proportion of individuals in each county that have obtained a high school degree or higher, the proportion of individuals with a bachelor’s degree or higher, and the unemployment rate of each county.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project1</title>
      <link>/project1_sds348/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1_sds348/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The two datasets included in this project are Texas Education and Employment by county (CountyEducationEmployment) and Texas Income by county (CountyIncome), both obtained from the Texas Association of Counties. The Texas Education and Employment dataset contains the proportion of individuals in each county that have obtained a high school degree or higher, the proportion of individuals with a bachelor’s degree or higher, and the unemployment rate of each county.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are the projects I completed this semester:
  Project 1: (Data Wrangling and Exploratory Analysis)
  Project 2: Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>